A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of the Secretary and General Counsel, Grant Records, Organizational Grants FA1510
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Recommended Grant Action Forms and Affirmative Action Statements, 1
  - American Council on Education, 1974-1985 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    1977 - General support 1985 - Partial support of an Office of Minority Concerns working with all U.S. higher education
    1983 - Support for study of the effects of state oversight of the affairs of state universities
    1980 - Support for the establishment of a Division of International Educational Relations
    1977 - General support
    1976 - Support for a Commission Intercollegiate Athletics
    1975 - Partial support of the 1975 Annual Meeting
    1974 - Support for surveys and analyses on alternate methods for determining instructional costs
    1976 - Support of the International Education Project, Supplement No. 1
  - American Dance Festival (WJH), 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    1980 - Financial stabilization of the Festival in its new location
    1978 - To help restructure Festival in its new location and insure cooperation with North Carolina School of the Arts
  - The American Dance Machine, Inc., 1979 July (Box 2, Folder 62)
    Management supplement
  - American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research, 1974-1986 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    1986 February - Congressional seminar series on economic policy issues of major importance to the U.S.
    1984 November - Partial support for a study by Meron Benvenisti of the Israeli government's policy in the West Bank area, including legal aspects, land policy, demographics and economics. Supplement No. 2
    1984 September - Partial support for research on the factors that have promoted or impeded different countries' adjustment to international disturbances
    1983 December - Partial support for a study by Meron Benvenisti of the Israeli government's policy in the West Bank area, including legal aspects, land policy, demographics and economics. Supplement No. 1
    1983 March - Partial support for a study by Meron Benvenisti of the Israeli government's policy in the West Bank area, including legal aspects, land policy, demographics and economics.
    1974 July - Partial support for a review of recent wage and price controls in the United States
    1974 January - Study of the major legislative implications of the facts emerging from the hearings of the Senate Select Committee on Presidential Activities
  - American Federation of Teachers (AFT), 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    1980 - development of college programs for working adults
    1977 - development and publication of a television program supplement for its quarterly journal American Educator
  - American Foundation for the Blind, Inc., 1979 February (Box 2, Folder 65)
    For partial support to write a book on blindness
  - American Friends of the Middle East, 1974 April (Box 2, Folder 66)
    Support for overseas educational services in the Middle East, Supplement No. 4
  - American Friends Service Committee #67-241, 1974-1986 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    1986 June - Support for rights litigation in the West Bank
    1986 February - Partial support for public education work concerning refugees and migrants, and for model refugee women's projects
    1985 May - Support for community development activities in Zimbabwe's Communal Lands
    1984 September - Support to local and regional programs in the Southeastern U.S. to improve employment opportunities for low-income rural women, Supplement No. 2
    1984 August - Support for expansion and consolidation of Rural Women's Advisory Committee's income generation projects in Mali
    1983 September - Support to local and regional programs in the Southeastern U.S. to improve employment opportunities for low-income rural women, Supplement No. 1
    1982 September - Support to local and regional programs in the Southeastern U.S. to improve employment opportunities for low-income rural women
    1981 May - Continued partial support for the Southeastern Public Education Program
    1981 April - Support for West Africa Women in Development Program
    1978 January - Affirmative Action Plan
    1978 February - Support for seminars in arms limitation and security issues for members of UN delegations primarily from small non-aligned Third World countries
    1974 February - Continued general support of the activities of the Family Aid Fund
    1977 May - Support for AFSC's Public Education Program's efforts to combat racism and sexism in desegregated public schools
  - American Indian Development Association, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    Continued support to a Native American technical assistance institution
  - American Indian Higher Education Consortium (AIHEC), 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    1981 - Support to continue publication of Wassaja, a national Indian magazine
    1980 - To install new management systems in 17 Tribally controlled 2-year colleges
    1978 - Support for a project to develop criteria and standards for accreditation of Indian-controlled two-year colleges on or near American Indian reservations
  - American Indian Historical Society (#760-0053), 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    1979 - Continued partial support for Wassaja, a national Native American newspaper
    1977 - Partial support for the publication and distribution of a national Native American newspaper
    1974 - Continued support to a Native American technical assistance organization (Grant No. 740-0039)
    1975 - Partial support for the publication and distribution of a national Native American newspaper
  - American Indian Lawyer Training Program, 1985 August (Box 2, Folder 71)
    Support to initiate training and educational program for Native American leaders and natural resource managers
  - American Institute of Indian Studies, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    1985 May - To fund a series of university-based conferences in conjunction with Festival of India, Supplement No. 1
    1982 May - Matching grants for endowment funds
    1981 June - General support
    1981 September - Establishment of an archive and research center in ethnomusicology in India
  - American Institutes for Research in Behavioral Sciences, 1975-1985 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    1985 January - Supplemental support to operate a national arson prevention demonstration and to document the results (830-0578)
    1983 June - Support to develop and launch a national arson prevention demonstration and to document the results
    1980 December - Support for the fourth and final phase of a national child care information and referral services demonstration (800-0522)
    1979 December - Support for Phase III of a four phase study of child care information and referral services (780-0192)
    1979 March - Support for Phase II of a four phase study of child care information and referral services (780-0192)
    1978 January - Support for first phase of a four phase research and demonstration program focused on child care information and referral
    1975 October - Support of research and workshops on retirement age policy
  - American Jewish Committee, 1974 June (Box 2, Folder 74)
    Supplement to Grant 71-69, Support for the National Project on Ethnic America
  - American Judicature Society, 1986 April (Box 2, Folder 75)
    General support of programs to expand citizen involvement in efforts to improve the judicial system in the U.S.
  - American Music Theater Festival, Philadelphia, 1986 January (Box 2, Folder 76)
    Support for a Music Theater Production Alliance to foster the creation and production of new work
  - American National Theatre and Academy, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    Partial support for development of the technology for video-taping staged plays
  - American ORT Federation, Inc., 1983 September (Box 2, Folder 78)
    Partial support for a training program in architectural drafting for female school leaders in Senegal
  - The Academy for Educational Development, Inc., 1975-1985 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    1985 August - Partial support for a pregnancy prevention initiative in the urban middle schools
    1985 April - Support to complete site visits of Urban Community College Transfer Opportunities Projects
    1984 March - Supplementary support for follow-up activities related to the City High School Recognition Program
    1982 November - To extend the City High School Recognition Program of awards/grants to selected high schools in 24 of the nation's largest cities
    1981 April - Analysis and report of state roles in governance of higher education
    1980 September - To test out and operate the Educational Resource Exchange
    1975 October - Partial non-renewable support for the operating expenses of a national office
  - The Albany Report, 1974 June (Box 2, Folder 80)
    Support for the publication of monthly magazines on state government affairs in New York and Illinois
  - The Allegheny West Foundation, 1984 September (Box 2, Folder 81)
    Partial support for five CDCs and a technical assistance organization in partnership with the Pew Memorial Trust and the City of Philadelphia
  - The American Academy of Diplomacy, 1984 September (Box 2, Folder 82)
    Support to devise an independent and authoritative review system for ambassadorial appointments
  - The American Assembly, 1974-1983 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    1983 September - Partial support for a program on the central issues in the relationship between the United States and Canada
    1983 June - Partial support of an American Assembly on The Arts and Public Policy
    1981 June - Support for Arden House Conference on the policy implications of changing relations among ethnic groups in America
    1980 November - Support for an assembly on "Military Service in the United States"
    1978 March - Partial support of an American Assembly on corporate governance
    1975 May - Support of Assembly Program on Women in the American Economy
    1975 October - Partial support of an American Assembly on employment questions to held May 20-23, 1976
    1974 June - Support of United State and European conferences on policies and issues currently affecting museums of fine arts
    1974 May - Supplemental support for a special Assembly for Workers on the Changing World of Work
  - The American Association of School Administrators, 1977-1983 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    1983 February - To improve opportunities and preparation for women in school administration (Project AWARE)
    1981 November - Support for a national coalition of regional and local organizations working to increase the representation of women in administrative positions in elementary and secondary schools
    1980 October - Continued support for Project AWARE (Assisting Women to Advance Through Resources and Encouragement)
    1979 July - Support to launch Project AWARE (Assisting Women to Advance Through Resources and Encouragement)
    1977 February - Support for projects designed to achieve equality of treatment for women and girls in education and to develop in fifteen selected states a cadre of school administrators knowledgeable about and committed to school finance reform.
  - The American Conservatory Theatre Foundation, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    Support to improve and stabilize the company's financial position
  - The American Film Institute, 1980 June (Box 2, Folder 86)
    Support of a workshop program that helps aspiring women film directors to obtain directing jobs with major film studios
  - The American Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    Support for a civil rights education program in Israel
  - The Board of Trustees of the University of Alabama, 1983 September (Box 2, Folder 88)
    Support of community outreach demonstration program to improve pregnancy outcome and child health
  - University of Abidjan, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    1984 September - Support for staff development, research and new doctoral program at Ivorian Center for Economic and Social Research
    1982 August - Support for staff development and research program at Ivorian Center for Economic and Social Research
    1980 August - Support for the Ivorian Center for Economic and Social Research, Supplement No. 2
  - University of Alaska, 1975 May (Box 2, Folder 90)
    1) Supplemental support for the Center for Northern Educational Research (#72-248) for operating costs caused by "pipeline" inflation
    2) Alaskan School Finance Study
    3) A legal review of the statutes, scourt decisions and agency regulations governing Alaska Native education
  - The American Place Theatre, Inc., 1974-1983 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    1983 November - Support for Women's Project Training Program for Stage Directors
    1981 October - Workshop for women playwrights and directors
    1981 August - Support for the outreach program of the Women's Circle
    1980 November - Workshop for women playwrights and directors (760-0648A)
    1979 October - Workshop for women playwrights and directors (760-0648)
    1978 August - Workshop for women playwrights and directors
    1974 June - Experimentation in new artistic and electronic approaches to playhouse theater for television
  - Self-Employed Women's Association - Bharat, 1984 June (Box 3, Folder 92)
    Core support for a new national intermediary organization to assist self-employed women workers in India
  - Senahan, Inc., 1977 June (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - SER/Jobs for Progress, Inc., 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    1986 May - Support to establish Comprehensive Competencies Program learning centers
    1984 December - Support to establish Comprehensive Competencies Program (CCP) learning centers
  - SER Research Insitute (Colombia), 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    1986 March - Support for applied research on the Colombian judiciary
    1982 July - Support for collective fieldwork leading to six studies of rural education in Colombia
  - Service Center for the Development of Tehuacan, 1986 June (Box 3, Folder 96)
    Support for a savings and loans program for the rural poor
  - Seven League Productions, 1981 January (Box 3, Folder 97)
    Support for the production of three films focusing on three separate periods of Cuban experience in the U.S.
  - The Seventh Generation Fund for Indian Development, Inc., 1985 February (Box 3, Folder 98)
    Support for Native American technical assistance intermediary promoting natural resource-based tribal development
  - 70001, Ltd., 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Shakespeare & Co., Inc., 1981 April (Box 3, Folder 100)
    Support for minority participation in the Shakespeare and Company training program in classical theater
  - Shared Educational Experiences, Inc., 1976 September (Box 3, Folder 101)
    Matching support to help strengthen the staffing and financial base of the SEE program
  - Shreemati Nathibai Damodar Thackersey Women's University, 1981 May (Box 3, Folder 102)
    Support for strengthening the research unit on women's studies at the University
  - Sierra Club Legal Defense Fund, Inc., 1974-1979 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    1979 April - Support of a deferred-gifts program
    1978 January - General operating support (PA 710-0306, Supplement No. 5)
    1976 February - General support
    1974 March - Operating support
    1977 February - General operating support
  - The Sigma Delta Chi Foundation, 1985 February (Box 3, Folder 104)
    Support for development of a project to promote reporting on the Third World in local U.S. newspapers
  - Silveira House, Zimbabwe, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    1983 August - Promotion of small-scale development activities in Zimbabwe's former "tribal trust lands"
    1982 April - Promotion of small-scale development activities in Zimbabwe's former "tribal trust lands"
    1981 February - Promotion of small-scale development activities among previously dislocated groups in Zimbabwe's rural areas
  - A.N. Sinha Institute of Social Studies, 1983 May (Box 3, Folder 106)
    Strengthening the social sciences in India
  - Sisters of Providence in Washington, 1982 August (Box 3, Folder 107)
    Research on biochemical changes underlying the increased risk of cardiovascular disease in young women taking oral contraceptives
  - Small Farm Development Corporation, 1980 September (Box 3, Folder 108)
    Loan to finance land acquisition of experimental rural development project in the Southeast
  - Hobart and William Smith Colleges, 1974 June (Box 3, Folder 109)
    Venture Funds grants to Northeastern institutions in support of innovations in undergraduate education
  - Smith Pipe and Supply, Inc., 1980 September (Box 3, Folder 110)
    1) Loan for working capital purposes
    2) Loan to finance site development costs for new pipe testing an inspection facility
  - Smithsonian Institution (#70-185), 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    1981 - 1) Development of a minority managerial and curatorial personnel at the National Museum of American History; 2) Development of minority curatorial personnel at the Cooper-Hewitt Museum
    1979 - Support for research on "Ethnic Conflict in Developing Countries," Supplement No. 1
    1978 - Support for research on "Ethnic Conflict in Developing Countries"
  - Social Science Council of Nigeria, 1986 April (Box 3, Folder 112)
    Support for a social science research competition, workshop and conference on small-scale enterprises in the food processing and food distribution sector in Nigeria
  - The Social Science Foundation, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    1982 - To help create an endowmnet fund to support the Foundation's core operating costs
    1981 - professional advancement of women in the social sciences
  - The Social Science Research Council, 1974-1986 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    1986 January - Partial support for an Indochina refugee interview project
    1986 January - Partial support for a summer workshop on the Soviet and East European economics
    1986 January - Establishment of a fellowship program on the U.S. foreign policy making progress
    1985 October - Partial support for the establishment of a network of researchers addressing the African agricultural crisis through fellowships, workshops, and a clearinghouse of research materials
    1985 August - Support for the establishment of a joint committee on the comparative study of Muslim societies
    1985 May - Research projects supporting the investigation underway by the Project on Social Welfare and the American Future
    1985 May - Support for a public policy research competition on issues related to U.S. Hispanics
    1984 September - Partial support for a summer workshop on Soviet and East European economics
    1983 August - Partial support for an Indochinese refugee interview project
    1982 August - Support for the joint international committees of the Council and the American Council on Learned Societies
    1980 August - Support for research awards and research planning
    1979 December - Research planning and initiation activities of the Joint Committee on Latin American Studies, Supplement No. 2
    1979 August - Support for interdisciplinary research of the subcommittee on South Asian Political Economy
    1979 May - Research awards program for Asian, Middle East and African, Latin American and West European Studies and research planning activities
    1979 January - To improve and stabilize its financial position
    1978 September - Research awards program for Asian, Middle East and African, Latin American and West European Studies, Supplement No. 1
    1978 August - Research and conference programs, Supplement No. 1
    1976 November - 1) Support for the Joint Committee on African Studies, Supplement No. 6; 2) Assistance to Joint Committee on Near and Middle East, Supplement No. 3; 3) Support for predoctoral and research fellowships on Africa and the Middle East, Supplement No. 6
    1976 September - 1) Support for research and other scholarly activities about Asia
    1976 August - Fellowship, internship, and research awards vis-a-vis Latin American, Supplement No. 5
    1975 December - Support for Western Europe Doctoral Research Fellowship Program, Supplement No. 5 (Formerly: Support for West Europe Fellowship Program
    1974 - 1) Support for the Joint Committee on African Studies, Supplement No. 4; 2) Assistance to Joint Committee on Near and Middle East, Supplement No. 4
    1974 September - Support for Asian Foreign Area Fellowship Program, Supplement No. 4
    1974 August - Fellowship, internship, and research awards vis-a-vis Latin American, Supplement No. 3
    1973 December - 1) Support for the Joint Committee on African Studies, Supplement No. 3; 2) Assistance to Joint Committee on Near and Middle East, Supplement No. 1; 3) Support for postdoctoral and research fellowships on Africa and the Middle East, Supplement No. 3
    1975 August - Fellowship, internship, and research awards vis-a-vis Latin American, Supplement No. 4
    1975 November - 1) Support for the Joint Committee on African Studies, Supplement No. 5; 2) Assistance to Joint Committee on Near and Middle East, Supplement No. 2; 3) Support for predoctoral and research fellowships on Africa and the Middle East, Supplement No. 5
    1977 September - Research and conference programs
  - Social Work and Research Centre, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    1986 - Support for resource management capacity building in a private voluntary organization
    1981 - Support for village-level action research and demonstration projects for intensive fuelwood and fodder farming through Mahila Mandal and experimental projects in small-scale irrigation
  - Society for Education, Action and Research in Community Health (SEARCH), 1986 May (Box 3, Folder 116)
    Support for community-oriented rural health services, training, and research
  - Society for International Development, 1978 February (Box 3, Folder 117)
    Support of North/South Roundtable and other activities
  - Society for Promotion of Wastelands Development (India), 1983 May (Box 3, Folder 118)
    Support for efforts to promote the development of wastelands through afforestation, and planting fuelwood trees in degraded areas
  - Society for Service to Voluntary Agencies, 1985 March (Box 3, Folder 119)
    Core support for work on child survival problems in India
  - South African Council of Churches, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    1985 September - Administrative and salary support for university scholarship selection, secondary-level tutorials and social research
    1985 August - Network of ecumenical Justice and Reconciliation Fieldworkers to promote sharing of information and resources on legal and other community advice services
    1984 August - Administrative support for the coordination of a collaborative fellowship program for black South Africans
    1983 September - Administrative support for the coordination of a collaborative fellowship program for black South Africans
    1982 September - Administrative support for the coordination of a collaborative fellowship program for black South Africans
  - The University of Southampton (United Kingdom), 1984 March (Box 3, Folder 121)
    Research on the security relations between the northern industrialized countries and the Third World
  - South Bronx Community Housing Corporation, 1980 April (Box 3, Folder 122)
    For legal and management assistance
  - South Bronx Development Organization, Inc., 1982 August (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - State of South Carolina - Office of the Governor, 1983 April (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - South East Alabama Self-Help Association (SEASHA), 1974-1984 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    1984 April - General administrative and program support (720-0194)
    1983 April - Administrative support for community development
    1980 February - Continued general support to a CDC operating in 12 rural counties in Alabama